Ning Xie

Personal Details

Address | Am Brunnenbächli 2, 8125 Zollikerberg

Phone +41 (0)78 402 70 41

E-mail ningxie1991@gmail.com

Permit B (EU Familiennachzug)

Website ning-xie.com

LinkedIn <u>linkedin.com/in/ning-xie</u>



Profile and Objective

I am an experienced software engineer in constant pursuit of elegant solutions, clean code and innovative approaches. With a solid background in computer science and seven years in the FinTech industry, I have gained the business knowhow, solution design skills and the ability to effectively collaborate with diverse stakeholders and fellow software engineers in an agile working environment. I look forward to apply my past experience, my passion in software development and my interest in AI in the next professional role within the digital innovation industry.

Professional Experience

Sep 2022 – present

Senior Software Engineer (full time), Synpulse8/Synpulse Schweiz AG, Zürich, Switzerland

- Core backend developer for our proprietary Wealth Backend integration services for the OpenWealth API standards written in Java, OpenAPI and Spring Integration Framework
- Core frontend developer for the Relationship Manager Advisory Dashboard (rebranded as Wealth Cockpit) web application written in React, TypeScript, Tailwindcss and Java
- Researched and designed the architecture for our proprietary enterprise React frontend component library and implemented the solution within 4 months
- Established frontend standards across the whole group by integrating the component library as a basis for all our React frontend client projects

Jun – Dec 2021 Web Developer (part time 40%), Computational Evolution Group, ETH, Zürich, Switzerland

• Improved the design and features on the <u>CoV-Spectrum</u> website, an interactive visualization tool to track and identify the variants of coronavirus, using React, TypeScript and Tailwind

Sep 2019 – Aug 2020 Senior Software Engineer (full time), Wellington Management Company, Boston, USA

 Programed and maintained the complex backend services for the proprietary trading platform using Java, with deployment and quarterly release responsibilities as a core Java and DevOps engineer (promoted to senior in 2019)

Apr 2015 -Aug 2019

- Software Engineer (full time), Wellington Management Company, Boston, USA
 - Developed a suite of 7 web applications written in Angular, React, JavaScript and Spring Boot
 - Migrated web applications and infrastructure to cloud-based on Amazon Web Services
 - Ensured the reliability of critical functions and services by resolving production level failure incidents as a member of the production support team

Summer 2014

Game Developer (intern), MassDiGI, Becker College, Worcester, USA

 Programmed C# scripts for gameplay logic and UI for the mobile tower-defense game named "Midnight Terrors" and released the game to <u>iOS</u> app store under MassDiGI

Technical Skills

UI/UX

Requirements Analysis, Prototyping, Figma, Material-UI, Tailwindcss

Coding

Java, Spring Boot, REST API, GraphQL, React, JavaScript, TypeScript, CSS, HTML5, Python

Database

- SQL, NoSQL, Spring Data, SPARQL, RDF, OWL, Knowledge Graph
- DevOps Maven, Gradle, Docker, GitHub Actions, AWS, Google Cloud, Kubernetes, CI/CD

Certificates

UI/UX Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design (Google)

Front-end | Modern React with Redux (Udemy)

Education

Sep 2020 – Master of Science in Informatics, Summa Cum Laude, University of Zürich, Switzerland

Dec 2022 | Major: People-Oriented Computing Minor: Informatics

GPA: 5.5 / 6.0

Published Thesis: Federated Trust: A solution for trustworthy federated learning

2011 - 2015 | **Bachelor in Computer Science**, Mount Holyoke College, *Massachusetts, USA*

Major: Computer Science Minor: Mathematics

GPA: 3.6 / 4.0

Semester abroad: Aquincum Institute of Technology, Budapest, Hungary

Academic Projects Highlight (master's level)

Fall 2021 Semantic Annotation Framework (Master Project), DDIS Group, University of Zürich

 Designed and developed a Chrome extension to annotate the web and create RDF data for arguments, hypotheses and data science workflows using semantic web technologies

Fall 2021 Movie Chatbot, Advanced Topics in AI Module, University of Zürich

 Designed and implemented a chatbot to answer movie related questions using Python, sparql and a knowledge graph

Spring 2021 | AScout, Advanced Software Engineering Module, University of Zürich

 Designed and developed a web application for vacation rental neighborhood scouting using Airbnb open dataset, Google Cloud Maps API, React, Java, Spring, MongoDB

Language skills Interests

Chinese	Native Speaker	Dancing	2nd place at 2014 KPOP World Festival, NYC
English	Proficient	Travelling	Visited 16 countries and counting
German	Basic	Skiing	Ventured onto red slopes this past season
Korean	Basic	Running	Ran in SOLA-Stafette 2022 for IFI Runners team